Guide to the Lucy Maynard Salmon Papers, 1818-1992 (bulk 1854-1933)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE — To and From Others
  - Others to Others
    - Fox, Helene to Miss Borden, 19 Apr (1932); (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Gaula, George W. to Mr. Maynard, 1840, 1843; (3 letters, 1 on reverse of Eaton letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Gillmour, James to unknown, 22 Aug 1871; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Gordy, Wilbur F. to Etta Sinsabaugh, 31 May 1906; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Hubbard, Margaret to Pomeroy, 8 July 1913; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Hunting, Frances A. to Lucy Maynard Sloss, 17 Apr 1902; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Larrabee, Rachel to Louise Fargo Brown, 1936; (2 letters) (Folder 28.9)
    - Larrabee, Rachel to Office of the President Vassar College, 9 June 1938; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Lauder, Estelle to Louise Fargo Brown, 28 Feb 1940; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Leete, Charles H. to James Monroe Taylor, 10 Apr 1908; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Lowrie, Rebecca to Mrs. Clarke, 28 Apr 1936; (1 letter) (Folder 28.9)
    - Lyman, Frank to Pom, [1878]; (2 letters) (Folder 28.9)
    - MacCracken, Henry Noble to others, 1916-1937; (5 letters, 1 carbon copy) (Folder 29.1)
    - Others to Henry Noble MacCracken (with report card of M.N. Hudson), 1914-1937; (4 letters, 3 TS) (Folder 29.3)
    - Maynard, Ed to Pom, 3 Mar 1877; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Maynard, Margaret to Lucille, 14 Nov 1922; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - McCaleb, Ella to Etta Sinsabaugh, 21 Oct 1904; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - McMurtrie, Douglas C. to Fanny Borden, 10 Sep 1940; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Orendorff, Margaret R. M. to Mrs. George Edward Clark, 14 Sep 1937; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Patterson, Irene E. to unknown, 28 Feb 1936; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Perkins, Emma to Dr. Taylor, 5 Mar 1898; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Piper, C.H. to Mrs. Lucy Maynard, 5 Mar 1841; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Piper, Sibbil to Mrs. Lucy Maynard, 15 Sep 1842; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Reed, Amy L. to Mary E. Hurlbutt, 27 June 1916; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Reed, L.M. to Pomeroy, 9 Nov 1870; (1 letter) (Folder 29.9)
    - Rhoads, James to unknown, 14 Apr 1886; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Richardson, E.C. to A.L.A. Meeting, [1913]; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Others to Caroline E. Page Salmon, 1869-1876; (4 letters, 1 invitation, 2 TS) (Folder 29.4)
    - Salmon, George to Frederick Lyman, 1842-1866; (9 letters) (Folder 29.2)
    - Salmon, George to Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Whaley (Folder 46.14)
    - Others to George Salmon, 1841-1862; (15 letters, 1 enclosure) (Folder 29.5)
    - Salmon, Rosene Alsada Van Dusen to Brainard, undated; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Sellers, Clifford West to Officers of Vassar College, 2 May [1921]; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Stuart, Cora to Miss Updegraff, 10 July 1927; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Taylor, James Monroe to Frances Wood, 1 June 1910; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Truesdale, Julia Brooks to Louise Fargo Brown, [1936?]; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Weeks, Lyman to VC Library, 10 Oct 1911; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Williams, Alice to Lucy Andrews, 18 July 1926; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Williams, Talcott to James Monroe Taylor, 25 Dec 1896; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
    - Unidentified to Miss Dutcher, 8 Sep 1915; (1 letter) (Folder 29.10)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS
  - Manuscripts and Notes
    - Manuscripts — Chronological
      - Short Essays, 1861-1872, undated; (26 essays, 5 TS) (Folder 34.4)
      - Short Essays, 1867-1868; (1 notebook) (Folder 34.5)
      - Language Exercises, circa 1871; (1 notebook) (Folder 34.6)
      - "An Analysis of the Characters of Achilles, Ulysses, Hector, and Nestor" (incomplete), 1873; (20 pages) (Folder 34.7)
      - "Abstract of Ars Poetica,", 1874; (16 pages) (Folder 34.8)
      - Untitled essay, 1874; (13 pages) (Folder 34.9)
      - "Abstract of the Third Satire of Juvenal,", 1874; (13 pages) (Folder 34.10)
      - "Sophocles,", 1874; (9 pages) (Folder 34.11)
      - "... Debating is a Useful Exercise: Negative "... Debating is a Useful Exercise: Positive,", 1875; (5 pages, 5 pages) (Folder 34.12)
      - "The Political Spirit of England...,", 1875; (34 pages) (Folder 34.13)
      - "What was the Political Condition of England Under the Saxons?", 1876; (19 pages) (Folder 34.14)
      - "The Organization of the Judiciary in the US. ...,", 1876; (20 pages) (Folder 34.15)
      - [Hamilton and Jefferson], 1876; (MS) (Folder 58.1)
      - "Establishment of Representative Government,", 1882; (TS) (Folder 58.2)
      - "English Reviews,", 1883; (MS) (Folder 58.3)
      - "Another View of the Colonial Policy of England, 1887; (MS) (Folder 58.4)
      - Series of lectures given at Vassar College on the definitions, purposes and sources of history, [circa 1890?]; (MS) (Folder 58.5)
      - "Some Economic Aspects of Domestic Service,", 1893; (TS) (Folder 58.6)
      - "Profit Sharing in Domestic Service," inc. draft of a 1919 letter from LMS to George W. Perkins on profit sharing, [1894?]; (TS, 1 letter) (Folder 58.71)
      - "The Development of Domestic Service: Its Economics and Ethics,", 1897; (TS) (Folder 58.7)
      - "Teaching of History in Germany," including letter from F. Urtel, [1897?]; (MS) (Folder 58.8)
      - "Some Economic Questions Concerning Domestic Service,", 1898; (TS) (Folder 58.9)
      - "Education in America,", circa 1898; (MS) (Folder 58.10)
      - [Relations Between the United States and England], circa 1898; (MS) (Folder 58.11)
      - Untitled essay written in French while studying in Paris, with corrections by instructor, 1898 or 1899; (MS) (Folder 58.12)
      - Letter to the Editor of The Times on the U.S. Constitution and Acts of Congress, 13 May 1899; (MS) (Folder 38.14)
      - "The Leaven of Society,", 1900; (TS) (Folder 58.13)
      - "An American School of History in Rome,", 1901; (TS) (Folder 58.14)
      - "History on Stone and Canvas,", 1901; (TS and MS) (Folder 58.15)
      - "Housekeeping,", 1901; (MS) (Folder 58.16)
      - [Coeducation at the University of Chicago], circa 1902; (MS) (Folder 58.17)
      - "The Training of the Observation Through the Study of History,", 1903; (MS) (Folder 58.18)
      - "By-Products in Scandinavia,", 1905; (2 TS) (Folder 58.19)
      - "The Middle States Convention of History Teachers," inc. letter from The Nation rejecting it for publication, 1905; (TS) (Folder 58.20)
      - Poetry - "To an Iceberg" and "To the Sea,", 1905-1909; (20 pages) (Folder 35.1)
      - Letter to the Editor of Evening Post, 28 Mar 1910; (MS - fragment) (Folder 38.14)
      - "Why Does History Need to Be Rewritten,", circa 1910; (TS) (Folder 58.21)
      - "The University of Michigan at Vassar College," Michigan Alumnus, Dec 1913; (TS) (Folder 58.22)
      - [Historical Records], Apr 1914; (TS) (Folder 58.23)
      - "Main Street", circa 1915; (MS) (Folder 58.24)
      - "The New Issue" [the Presidential campaign and Woodrow Wilson], 1916; (TS) (Folder 58.25)
      - President Wilson as an Autophotographer,", 1916; (2 TS) (Folder 58.26)
      - "Woodrow Wilson,", [1916?]; (TS) (Folder 58.27)
      - Book review of Why Men Fight by Bertrand Russell, 1917; (TS) (Folder 58.28)
      - "Progress in Education at Vassar College,", circa 1917; (TS) (Folder 58.29)
      - "An Experience in Alcoholism" [perhaps about "William], circa 1917; (2 TS) (Folder 58.30)
      - "Smith Inc.,", circa 1917-1919; (TS) (Folder 58.31)
      - "The Golden Egg", 1918; (TS) (Folder 58.32)
      - "The Educational Disabilities of Women" and a copy of a letter by Lucy Maynard Salmon on recognition of women, 1918; (TS, 1 letter) (Folder 58.33)
      - "...the Purchase of Historical Material for Vassar College Library,", 1919; (2 pages) (Folder 35.2)
      - "What is a College for?" reprinted from the Vassar Quarterly, 1920; (MS) (Folder 58.34)
      - "Academic Unrest" (plan for a book of essays), circa 1920; (TS) (Folder 58.35)
      - LMS' response to "Assessing the Blame for the World War," Current History, June 1924; (TS) (Folder 58.36)
      - "New Bonds with Greece" (about Ida Carleton Thallon Hill), circa 1924; (corrected TS) (Folder 58.37)
      - "The Ubiquitous Laundry List," reprinted from the Vassar Miscellany News, 1925; (pamphlet) (Folder 58.38)
      - Why is History Rewritten? — Draft, circa 1925 (Folders 58.39 - 58.43)
      - Why is History Rewritten? — Notes, "precious memoranda," and miscellaneous (Folder 58.44)
      - Letter to the editor of the New York Times on the question of the greatest American historian, 1926; (TS) (Folder 58.45)
      - Historical Material — Draft, circa 1920s (Folders 58.46 - 58.47)
      - Historical Material — Notes and superseded material (Folder 58.48)
      - Historical Material — Draft (Folders 59.1 - 59.2)
    - Manuscripts — Undated, in alphabetical order
      - "The Common School Course in History,", undated; (TS) (Folder 58.49)
      - "Education and Politics in France,", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.50)
      - "The Evolution of the Teacher,", undated; (TS) (Folder 58.51)
      - "An Inquiry Concerning the Endowment of Colleges for Women and the Gifts Made to Them,", undated; (2 TS) (Folder 58.52)
      - "Minority Report on Music Courses" [at Vassar College], undated; (MS) (Folder 58.53)
      - "The Newspaper in School,", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.54)
      - "An Ode: On the Sink,", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.55)
      - [The Origin of Brahminism], undated; (MS) (Folder 58.56)
      - "Other Worlds,", undated; (TS) (Folder 58.57)
      - "Our Kitchens", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.72)
      - "A Plan for Affiliating Historical Societies,", undated; (MS - found in LMS' desk) (Folder 58.58)
      - "Trip to New Orleans,", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.59)
      - "Work for Alumnae,", undated; (MS) (Folder 58.60)
      - Adams, George H. S. "Should America Imitate the Expansion of England?", undated; (with LMS corrections) (Folder 35.16)
    - Research Notes
      - [Education] — Notes and fragments (Folders 58.61 - 58.62)
      - "Fans" — Notes and drafts, (TS) (Folders 58.63 - 58.65)
      - [History Teaching] — Notes (Folder 58.66)
      - [Taxation] — Notes and a copy of a 1919 letter criticizing the income tax because of its effect on women (Folder 58.67)
      - "Texas vs. White, et al" — Notes (Folder 58.68)
      - [Union of Utrecht] — Notes (Folder 58.69)
      - Miscellaneous notes, statements, and fragments (Folder 58.70)
  - Published Material
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1887-1923, undated; (5 photocopied news clippings) (Folder 33.3)
    - Bibliographies and published versions of her writings, arranged chronologically, 1885-1933 (Boxes 61-62)
  - Correspondence regarding publications
    - Correspondence about "The Family Cook Book," Vassar Quarterly, March 1926 (Folder 49.1)
    - Correspondence and reviews relating to Historical Material (NY: Oxford, 1933) (Folder 49.1)
    - Correspondence relating to "History in a Back Yard"(1912 address included in Historical Material ), including letters from Carl Becker, Father Francis Donnelly, and Julia Lathrop (Folder 49.1)
    - Letter from Louise P. Kellogg on Lucy Maynard Salmon brochure, What Is Modern History, 1917 (Folder 49.1)
    - Letter by Lucy Maynard Salmon on historical museums (Folder 49.1)
    - Items on the Ulster County Gazette and notes (Folder 49.1)
    - Correspondence, readers' comments, and reviews relating to Why is History Rewritten? NY: Oxford, 1929. Includes correspondence with Edward Cheyney and Carl Becker. (Folder 49.2)
    - Letters to Adelaide Underhill acknowledging receipt of Our Guests: Mary Ann and Her Predecessors, by Lucy Maynard Salmon (privately printed, 1929) (Folder 57.25)
- SERIES V. BIOGRAPHY AND PERSONAL
  - General
    - Personal journal of L.M. Salmon, undated; (1 volume) (Folder 36.1)
    - News clippings about L.M. Salmon, 1887-1927; (22 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.4)
    - News clippings about L.M. Salmon, 1927-1976, undated; (16 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.5)
    - Kellogg, Amherst W. "A Sonnet to Lucy Maynard Salmon...,", undated; (1 page, 2 copies) (Folder 35.5)
    - Works about L.M. Salmon (includes memorial addresses), 1905-1943, undated; (9 items) (Folder 30.1)
    - Fulton and Oswego Falls, NY — News clippings, 1890-1891; (13 articles) (Folder 33.6)
    - Fulton, NY, 1901; (1 brochure) (Folder 30.3)
    - Certificates, 1865-1914; (6 items) (Folder 38.5)
  - Family and Genealogy
    - Lyman family, undated; (3 pages) (Folder 37.1)
    - Lyman family - News clippings, 1920, undated; (2 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.12)
    - Maynard family, 1905-1918, undated; (16 pages) (Folder 37.2)
    - Maynard family - wedding announcements, 1892-1923; (4 items) (Folder 37.3)
    - Maynard family - News clippings, 1893; (1 article photocopied) (Folder 33.13)
    - Salmon family, 1851-1919, undated; (10 pages) (Folder 37.4)
    - Salmon Family - News clippings, 1839-1922, undated; (30 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.14)
    - Financial affairs of Mr. and Mrs. Kirtland Salmon, 1916 (Folder 46.29)
    - Will of Pomeroy L. Salmon (See also wills of Lucy Maynard Salmon in 47.11), 1906; (3 pages) (Folder 38.6)
  - Education
    - Falley Seminary, 1855-1922; (3 catalogues, 2 programs, 1 invitation) (Folder 30.4)
    - Fulton Female Seminary, 1837-1956, undated; (3 catalogues, 4 leaflets) (Folder 30.5)
    - Fulton Falley Seminary — News clippings, 1888-1956, undated; (23 articles - 22 photocopied) (Folders 33.7 - 33.9)
    - Fulton Falley Seminary — The Gleaner (student publication), 1837-1839; (13 issues) (Folders 35.13 - 35.14)
    - Fulton Falley Seminary — The Depository (student publication), 1837-1839; (9 issues) (Folder 35.15)
    - Fulton Falley Seminary — Record Book, 1836-1842; (1 volume) (Folder 36.7)
    - Fulton Falley Seminary — Book Listing Members, 1837-1839; (1 volume) (Folder 36.8)
    - Ann Arbor High School, 1892; (1 invitation) (Folder 30.6)
    - University of Michigan — General, 1873-1926, undated; (17 items) (Folder 31.2)
    - University of Michigan — News clippings, 1874-1878; (12 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.11)
    - University of Michigan — "Q. Ceekers" program agendas, 1875-1876, undated; (11 pages) (Folder 37.13)
    - University of Michigan — Address to the "Q. Ceekers,", 1876; (20 pages) (Folder 35.11)
    - University of Michigan — Works of the "Q. Ceekers,", 1875, undated; (4 items, 2 TS) (Folder 35.12)
    - University of Michigan — Chamberlin, Rose. "The True Womanly Woman,", circa 1875; (2 pages) (Folder 35.3)
    - University of Michigan — Concert programs, 1874-1876, undated; (11 programs) (Folder 30.7)
    - University of Michigan — Class Day exercises, 1873-1876; (3 programs) (Folder 30.8)
    - University of Michigan — Commencement Exercises, 1872-1926; (8 programs, 6 tickets) (Folder 30.9)
    - University of Michigan — Class of 1876 (includes reunion programs and address lists), 1879-1902; (13 items) (Folder 31.1)
    - University of Michigan — Fellowship Fund [raised by female graduates of UM], circa 1889; (15 pages) (Folder 37.11)
    - University of Michigan — Fellowship Fund [raised by female graduates of UM], circa 1889; (2 booklets) (Folder 37.12)
  - Academic Positions
    - McGregor High School — News clippings, 1878-1880, undated; (7 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.10)
    - McGregor High School, 1877-1880; (4 programs, 1 catalogue) (Folder 31.3)
    - Indiana State Normal School, 1886-1887; (1 catalogue, 2 leaflets) (Folder 31.4)
    - Bryn Mawr College, undated; (2 leaflets) (Folder 31.5)
    - Bryn Mawr College — Satterthwaite, Sarah E. "One Year at Bryn Mawr: Memories of Lucy Maynard Salmon and the Six, by One of the Six,", 1936; (21 pages, TS) (Folder 35.8)
    - Offer to teach at Columbia Teachers College, 1902 (Folder 45.10)
    - Offer to teach at Summer School of the South, University of Tennessee, 1907 (Folder 45.11)
  - Death
    - In memory of Lucy Maynard Salmon and tributes to Lucy Maynard Salmon from President MacCracken, faculty, Associate Alumnae, letters and statements from former students and fellow historians (Father Francis Donnelly, Preserved Smith, Henry Osborn Taylor), and publication of memorial service addresses. (Folder 57.19)
    - Letters to Adelaide Underhill from relatives of Salmon, Lucy Maynard, February - April 1927 (Folder 57.20)
    - Letters to Adelaide Underhill extending sympathy or in acknowledgment, February 1927-1931 (Folders 57.21 - 57.24)
    - Wills of Lucy Maynard Salmon with notes and letters from her lawyer (Folder 47.11)
    - Last illness. Cards and letters from family and friends; obituary (Folders 47.12 - 47.13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Life member and a manager of Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association. Twelfth Annual Report, certificate of life membership, and invitation from Florence Cushing (VC 1874), 1911 (Folder 45.8)
    - 263 Mill St. Items about Lucy Maynard Salmon residence and about "William," a problem servant employed by her for many years. Included are letters from William and members of his family, and notes, publications, and clippings on alcohol. (Folders 45.12 - 45.13)
    - Trips to Europe. Includes letters of introduction, passenger lists, and passports, 1892 and 1894 (Folder 47.1)
    - Trips to Europe. Includes letters of introduction, 1897-1899 (Folder 47.2)
    - Trips to Europe. Includes letters of introduction, 1900-1909 (Folder 47.3)
    - Letters of introduction to visit German schools, 1897 (Folder 47.4)
    - Letters relating to education in England, France, and Germany, 1890s (Folder 47.5)
    - Bookplates. Correspondence, including a letter from the designer of Lucy Maynard Salmon bookplate, E.D. French, 28 July 1899 (Folder 47.6)
    - "Helping Hand." 12 letters, showing cooperation and helpfulness, 1889-1926 (Folder 47.7)
    - Business affairs, 1892-1934 (Folder 47.8)
    - Cash accounts of L.M. Salmon, 1866-1909; (20 pages) (Folder 37.16)
    - Zeal for work. Letters from Mary W. Whitney and Frances Wood, 1889-1895 (Folder 47.9)
    - Philosophy of life, sense of humor, a favorite story - notes, clippings, and 3 letters (Folder 47.10)
    - Copies of Salmon letters and excerpts from publications selected by Louise Fargo Brown. (Box 43)
    - Preliminary inventory of Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection, 1936; (12 pages) (Folder 37.5)
    - The Colgate Alumni Quarterly - volume I, no. 12, July 1912 (Folder 32.6)
    - Note cards of Lucy Maynard Salmon (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous news clippings, 1885-1924, undated; (15 articles photocopied) (Folder 33.15)
    - Miscellaneous cards, scraps and fragments (Folders 38.12 - 38.13)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Unidentified portraits, (2 photos on leather) (Folder 38.1)
  - Assorted photos, (23 photos) (Folder 38.2)
  - Edith C. Banfield (VC 1892) family, (2 photos) (Folder 38.3)
  - Assorted photos (including Falley Seminary), (7 photos) (Folder 38.4)
  - Salmon as a child (Folder 39.1)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon in the 1870s (Folder 39.2)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon in the 1880s and 1890s (Folder 39.3)
  - Portrait of Lucy Maynard Salmon by Katherine E. McClellan, 1905 (Folder 39.4)
  - Portrait of Lucy Maynard Salmon in her later years, 1920 (Folder 39.5)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon’s home in Rome, NY (Folder 39.6)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon’s room in Main Building; Salmon’s photographs of Rockefeller Hall (Folder 39.7)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon’s home at 263 Mill Street, Poughkeepsie (exterior views) (Folder 39.8)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon’s home at 263 Mill Street, Poughkeepsie (kitchen) (Folder 39.9)
  - Lucy Maynard Salmon’s grave (Folder 39.10)
  - The "Q. Ceekers" society at the University of Michigan [plate 8 in Apostle of Democracy ] (Folder 39.11)
  - The "Table Long" [plate 9 in Apostle of Democracy ] (Folder 39.12)
  - Portrait of Lucy Maynard Salmon by Katherine E. McClellan, [plate made for Apostle of Democracy ], 1905 (Folder 39.13)
  - Salmon Family photographs (Folder 40.1)
  - Photographs of Frank Salmon and unidentified others; postcards of Holland Patent, NY, 1924 and undated (Folder 46.28)
  - Unidentified photographs (Folder 40.2)
  - University of Michigan buildings (Folder 40.3)
  - Miss Keddie and her home in Oxford (Folder 40.4)
  - St. Mary’s City and River in Maryland (See also letter of 3/12/09 from Shattuck in Salmon 12.7) (Folder 40.5)
  - Daguerreotypes (unidentified), (19) (Box 41)
- SERIES VII. VASSAR COLLEGE
  - General
    - Faculty Committees — Includes Curriculum Committee business and correspondence, 1917-1923 (Folder 45.1)
    - Committee on the Curriculum — "Recommendations Presented to the Committee on the Curriculum,", undated; (4 pages) (Folder 37.10)
    - Committee on Intercollegiate Relations — Includes reports of the committee and correspondence with other faculty members and with President MacCracken, 1914-1916 (Folder 45.2)
    - Bureau of Publication — Communications with Burges Johnson. (Folder 45.3)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary of Vassar College — Correspondence, mostly replies to invitations, 1915 (Folder 45.4)
    - Lucy Maynard Salmon relations with alumnae and with Associate Alumnae of Vassar College — A collection of 48 letters, 1889-1926 (Folder 45.5)
    - Vassar Alumnae Historical Association — Information about organization, constitution, lists of members, reports of annual meetings, financial reports, gifts, bookplates, and correspondence, 1896-1912 (Folders 45.6 - 45.7)
    - Lucy Maynard Salmon Fund for Research — Information about the fund established in 1926, correspondence, and records of contributions. (Folder 45.9)
    - Lucy Maynard Salmon Fund for Research — Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Vassar College Library — The Mary Ann Collection of Books About Dogs (Folders 38.7 - 38.11)
    - Vassar College Library — Underhill, Adelaide. "Vassar College Library Historical Note,", 1935; (4 pages) (Folder 35.9)
    - Vassar College Library? — Anna Justice Fund - inventory of purchases, undated; (25 cards) (Folder 37.6)
    - Vassar College Library? — Anna Justice Fund - inventory of purchases, 1918-1923, undated; (28 pages) (Folder 37.7)
    - Vassar College Library? — Anna Justice Fund - financial records, 1907-1915; (4 booklets) (Folder 37.8)
    - Cash accounts of the "Steadfast Club" (for the benefit of Vassar College employees), 1890-1891; (9 pages, 1 booklet) (Folder 37.15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1902-1923; (2 leaflets) (Folder 31.8)
  - History Department
    - Annual reports, 1916-1919; (8 items) (Folder 37.9)
    - Entrance examinations, 1888-1911 (Folder 59.3)
    - Suggestion lists for reading (Folder 59.4)
    - "Records of Vassar College" — Humorous presentation by the Class in History S, 1915; (10 pages) (Folder 35.4)
    - Course outlines and examinations: Junior History, Senior History (Folder 59.5)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History 1 (Folder 59.6)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History 2 (Folder 59.7)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History A, History AA (Folder 59.8)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History B, History BB (Folder 59.9)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History C (Folder 59.10)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History D (Folder 59.11)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History E (Folder 59.12)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History F, History FF (Folder 59.13)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History G (Folder 59.14)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History H (Folder 59.15)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History M (Folder 59.16)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History O (Folder 59.17)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History R, History S (Folder 59.18)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History 11-12 (Folder 59.19)
    - Course outlines and examinations: History 43 (Folder 59.20)